Lou Harrison Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Lou Harrison Papers.
1946-1971
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Harrison, Lou.
.1 linear feet.
An American composer, Lou Harrison was born in 1917 and taught at Black Mountain College from 1951 until 1952.
MSS19980203
Biography
An American composer, Lou Harrison was born in 1917 and taught at Black Mountain College from 1951 until 1952.
Scope and Content
The collection contains manuscripts and correspondence concerning the publication of Harrison's About Carl Ruggles: Section Four of a Book on Ruggles (Yonkers, NY: Published by Oscar Baradinsky at the Alicat Bookshop, 1946), with an introduction by Henry Cowell. Included is Harrison's typescript, two versions of Cowell's introduction, and correspondence from Harrison and Ruggles to Baradinsky making significant changes in Cowell's introduction and commenting on the design of the book. Majority of the collection dates from 1946-1952.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of literary materials relating to Black Mountain College and the individuals associated with the institution. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Manuscripts.; Typescripts.
Occupations:
Composer.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Provenance unknown.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Papers, 1946-1971
  - “About Carl Ruggles” Harrison TS, undated (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - “Carl Ruggles” Cowell TS with corrections, undated (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - “About Carl Ruggles: A Note” Cowell TS, undated (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence
    - Cowell to Harrison (TLS), 1946 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Ruggles to Baradinsky (ALS), 1946 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Harrison to Baradinsky (ALS), 1946 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Harrison to Baradinsky (ALS), 1952 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Ruggles Obituary, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 8)